A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, 55th Street, Series 16 FA362
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files of Kathy Huldrum and Nancy Towell, 1970-1974; 5
  - Art Auction Materials, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 252)
    1974 article and material regarding the running of art auctions.
  - Arts and Entertainment Committee, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 253)
    Letters from NAR to individuals in the entertainment industry asking them to serve on the committee.
  - Biography of NAR, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 254)
    Biographical material on Nelson Rockefeller.
  - Buckley, James L. (Box 18, Folder 255)
    Newsletter of the New York Senator outlining an economic program.
  - Cambodia Operation and Response, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 256)
    Briefing paper on the American military operations into Cambodia from Vietnam in spring, 1970.
  - Clippings - "The New York Times Magazine", July 28, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 257)
    Article on the US economy. NAR has highlighted and made notations on the copy.
  - Clippings - "The Washington Post", August 21, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 258)
    Various articles concerning the announcement by President Ford selecting NAR to be Vice President.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Astor, Mrs. Vincent (Brooke), 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 259)
    1974 letter to Professor Fairbank regarding Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Booklets, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 260)
    Material that was available to the public outlining the goals of the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Budget - Budget, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 261)
    Planned expenditures for the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Budget - Budget Items, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 262)
    Items deducted from the budget submitted to NAR.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Budget - Budgets, Panels V and VI, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 263)
    Budgets for two of the panels from the commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Communications Program, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 264)
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 265)
    General correspondence file.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Draft Letter to Commission Members, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 266)
    for September 10, 1974 Meeting.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Bergsten, C. Fred, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 267)
    Letter from the Brookings Institution fellow on ideas for the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Braun, Theodore E., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 268)
    Correspondence from the head of Braun & company and a member of the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - deButts, John D., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 269)
    Correspondence from the head of AT&T.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Ford, Gerald R., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 270)
    Letter from Vice President Ford's Director of Scheduling regarding April meeting with NAR.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Free, Lloyd, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 271)
    Correspondence from the Johns Hopkins professor.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Logue, Edward J., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 272)
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Malik, Charles Habib, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 273)
    Letter from Malik, professor at the American University of Beirut.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Myerson, Bess, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 274)
    Letter from Panel II and VI member Myerson.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Rostow, Walter W., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 275)
    Materials on the Commission from Rostow, Professor at the University of Texas and frequent contributor of ideas to the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Sarnoff, Robert W., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 276)
    Letter from Sarnoff, Chairman and CEO of RCA Corporation, with a speech enclosed.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Swidler, Joseph C., 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 277)
    Letter from Swidler, chairman of NYS Public Service Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Weaver, Pat, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 278)
    Letter from Weaver offering his help.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Correspondence - Wilson, Carroll, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 279)
    Letter from Wilson, professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - March 27, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 280)
    Steering Committee
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - April 1-2, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 281)
    Held at the LBJ Library - Austin, Texas.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - May 28, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 282)
    Panel V Meeting, Presentation by Professor Bialer.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - August 12, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 283)
    Panel VI Meeting
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - August 14, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 284)
    Panel IV Meeting
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - September 10, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 285)
    Held at the Smithsonian Institution - Washington, D.C.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Meetings - December 4-5, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 286)
    Commission meeting.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Memoranda, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 287)
    Internal memoranda regarding the work of the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 288)
    Pending office file with documents for the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - NAR Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 289)
    Various notes taken by NAR at Commission meetings or ideas he had about the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel I, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 290)
    Energy, and its Relationship to Ecology, Economics, and World Stability. Clippings file.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel II, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 291)
    Food, Health, World Population & Quality of Life. Clippings file, letters from John Knowles and Walt Rostow.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel III, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 292)
    Raw Materials, Industrial Developments, Capital Formation, and World Trade. Clippings file, materials for meetings, charts, etc.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel IV, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 293)
    International Trade and Monetary Systems, Inflation, and the Relationships Among Differing Economic Systems. Clippings file, memoranda on Panel IV.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel V, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 294)
    Essential Elements of World Progress, Stability, and Peace. Clippings file, materials submitted by Walt Rostow and John S. Foster.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel VI, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 295)
    Quality of Life of Individuals and Communities in the United States. Preliminary drafts of ideas for Panel VI.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Panel VII, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 296)
    Public and Private Institutions in a Changing World. Draft for goals of Panel VII.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Reports - "The Age of Anxiety and Technology", 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 297)
    Report submitted by Sol M. Linowitz, co-chairman of the National Urban Coalition.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Reports - Design Issues, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 298)
    Submitted by Walter D. Littell regarding the logo design for the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Reports - "Economic Policy and the New Equality", 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 299)
    Report submitted by Paul W. McCracken, professor at the University of Michigan.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Reports - "Energy-The New Outlook", 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 300)
    Report submitted by Clifton C. Garvin, head of Exxon, from a speech he made.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Reports - Kissinger, Henry, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 301)
    Article by Kissinger from the March 16, 1974 issue of "The Economist." Papers on Western Europe and the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Reports - Lefkowitz, Louis J., 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 302)
    Attorney General of New York, sending June 22, 1974 issue of "The Nation" on the Reagan Years in California.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Speeches - February 1, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 303)
    Speech to the Bond Club outlining the goals of the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Speeches - March 5, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 304)
    Speech before the Regents Conference.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Speeches - April 30, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 305)
    Speech to Chase Bank International Council.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Study Outlines, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 306)
    Drafts for the various panels of the Commission.
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans - Third Century Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 307)
    Prospectus for the Commission.
  - Committee to Re-Elect the President (CREEP), 1973 (Box 20, Folder 308)
    Thank you letters to individuals who assisted in the New York efforts of reelecting President Richard M. Nixon.
  - Condolences on Death of Winthrop Rockefeller, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 309)
    Condolences received by NAR upon the death of his brother, Winthrop.
  - Correspondence on Vice Presidential Appointment (Box 20, Folder 310)
    Correspondence to individuals thanking them for supporting him to replace Vice President Agnew after his resignation.
  - Correspondence - Casey, William J., 1974 (Box 20, Folder 311)
    1974 letter to the President of the Senate from the head of the Export-Import Bank of the Untied States, regarding the loan, guarantee, and insurance transactions between the bank and several Eastern European countries, including the Soviet Union.
  - Correspondence - Galore, P. (Box 20, Folder 312)
    Letter from the entertainer offering her thanks to NAR for his service in Albany and asking to autograph a picture for her.
  - Correspondence - Gonzaga, G. B. Guerrieri (Box 20, Folder 313)
    Letter from the Italian artist to arrange a meeting.
  - Correspondence - Heller, Walter W. (Box 20, Folder 314)
    Letter from the University of Minnesota professor congratulating NAR on his nomination as Vice President.
  - Correspondence - Lincoln, G. A. (Box 20, Folder 315)
    Letter enclosing copy of remarks to be delivered at an event where NAR is to speak as well.
  - Correspondence - Pritchard, Sir Derek (Box 20, Folder 316)
    Correspondence file of the President of the Institute of Directors.
  - Correspondence - Thank You Letters, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 317)
    Various letters to individuals thanking them for their assistance with a NAR appearance.
  - Correspondence - Thank You Letters, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 318)
  - Correspondence - Woods, George D. (Box 20, Folder 319)
    Letter which enclosed is a survey on the "General Financial Situation."
  - Foundations (Box 20, Folder 320)
    Listing of Foundations located in the northeast United States.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - AFL-CIO Letters, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 321)
    Letters to labor leaders thanking them for support at the AFL-CIO convention.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Campaign Lists, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 322)
    Lists of campaign staff used for payroll.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Campaign Materials, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 323)
    Lists of the candidates up for reelection around the sate; lists of regional campaign coordinators.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Co-chairmen and Supporters, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 324)
    Letters of thanks from NAR to those individuals who supported his reelection or served as campaign co-chairs.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Contributions, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 325)
    Lists of people who gave money to the Rockefeller reelection campaign.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Contribution Thank You Letters (A-L), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 326)
    Thank you letters signed by NAR thanking individuals for their support of the campaign.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Contribution Thank You Letters (M-Z), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 327)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - County Republican Chairmen, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 328)
    Letters to the chairs of New York State county Republican chairmen after the state convention to thank them for support.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Election Results, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 329)
    Vote totals from around the state in the various contests.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Endorsements, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 330)
    Letters to individuals and newspapers that came out in support of NAR's reelection.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1970 (Box 21, Folder 331)
    Information on Goldberg, NAR's opponent in the election. Letter from Goldberg, NAR's response.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Labor Endorsements, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 332)
    Letters to labor leaders thanking them for their support of NAR in the election.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Labor Endorsements (A-B), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 333)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Labor Endorsements (C-E), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 334)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Labor Endorsements (F-M), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 335)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Labor Endorsements (O-P), 1970 (Box 22, Folder 336)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Labor Endorsements (S-U), 1970 (Box 22, Folder 337)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Lockwood, John, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 338)
    Letter to NAR on the national issues.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Lubell, Samuel, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 339)
    Reports from Samuel Lubell Associates, a polling organization that monitored the mood of the electorate.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Memoranda - Cannon, Jim, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 340)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Memoranda - Marshall, Alton G., 1970 (Box 22, Folder 341)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Memoranda - Morrow, Hugh, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 342)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Memoranda - Perrotta, Fioravante, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 343)
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Radio and TV Commercials, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 344)
    Transcripts of commercials for the campaign.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Rosenman, Samuel I., 1970 (Box 22, Folder 345)
    Materials from Rosenman, an advisor to NAR. Includes his suggestions for the fourth inaugural address.
  - Gubernatorial Reelection Campaign - Staff Meeting, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 346)
    Minutes of meeting from August 21, 1970.
  - Hahn Brothers, June 1974 (Box 22, Folder 347)
    2 receipts from June 1974 regarding the storage of several paintings.
  - Kissinger, Henry (Box 22, Folder 348)
    Memoranda regarding a meeting with the Governor of Puerto Rico that prior to scheduling was to be discussed with Kissinger.
  - Labor Reception Photo Letter, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 349)
    Letter to labor leaders offering a souvenir photo of them with NAR from a reception held in July 1970.
  - Liberman, Alexander (Box 22, Folder 350)
    Booklet from an exhibition of the artist's work in October, 1974 at a New York gallery.
  - March 1 Reception at 812 Fifth Avenue (Box 22, Folder 351)
    Listing of invitees to reception hosted by Mr. and Mrs. Rockefeller at their Fifth Avenue apartment. No year listed.
  - Memoranda - Hinman, George L. (Box 22, Folder 352)
  - Memoranda - Morrow, Hugh (Box 22, Folder 353)
  - Memoranda - Reed, J. V. (Box 22, Folder 354)
  - Memoranda - Whitman, Ann C. (Box 22, Folder 355)
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Letters to State Leaders, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 0355A)
    General note
    To meet the changing needs of the state of New York and the nation, Governor Rockefeller called upon state leaders to draft a proposal to see how New York could continue to lead the nation in a changing society. These files begin with the letter of request by NAR followed by the individual department's responses.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Attorney General, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 356)
    Louis Lefkowitz
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Banking Department, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 357)
    Headed by Commissioner Harry Albright
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Civil Service Commission, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 358)
    Headed by President Ersa H. Poston.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Council of Economic Advisors, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 359)
    Headed by Executive Director Robert Lindsay.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Agriculture and Markets, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 360)
    Headed by Commissioner Frank Walkley.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Audit and Control, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 361)
    Headed by State Comptroller Arthur Levitt.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Commerce, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 362)
    Headed by Commissioner Neil L. Moylan.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Correctional Services, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 363)
    Headed by Commissioner Russell G. Oswald.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Health, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 364)
    Headed by Commissioner Hollis S. Ingraham.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Labor, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 365)
    Headed by Industrial Commissioner Louis L. Levine.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Mental Hygiene, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 366)
    Headed by Commissioner Alan D. Miller.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Motor Vehicles, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 367)
    Headed by Commissioner Vincent L. Tofany.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Social Services, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 368)
    Headed by Commissioner Abe Lavine.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of State, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 369)
    Headed by Secretary of State John P. Lomenzo.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Taxation and Finance, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 370)
    Headed by Commissioner Norman F. Gallman.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Transportation, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 371)
    Headed by Commissioner Raymond T. Schuler.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Department of Youth, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 372)
    Headed by Director Milton Luger.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Division for Alcoholic Beverage Control, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 373)
    Headed by Chairman Bertram D. Sarafan.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Division of Criminal Justice, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 374)
    Headed by Archibald R. Murray.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Division of Housing and Community Control, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 375)
    Headed by Commissioner Charles J. Urstadt.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Division of Human Rights, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 376)
    Headed by Commissioner Jack M. Sable.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Division of Military and Naval Affairs, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 377)
    Headed by Major General John C. Baker.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Division of Veterans Affairs, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 378)
    Headed by Director Frank V. Votto.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Environmental Concerns, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 379)
    Submitted by Henry L. Diamond.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - "Institution of Free Enterprise", 1972 (Box 23, Folder 380)
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Insurance Concerns, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 381)
    Submitted by Benjamin R. Schenck.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Narcotic Addiction Control Commission, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 382)
    Headed by Howard A. Jones.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - New York State Education Department, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 383)
    Headed by Ewald B. Nyquist.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - New York State Education Department, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 384)
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - New York State Police, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 385)
    Headed by Superintendent William E. Kirwan.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Office for the Aging, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 386)
    Headed by Director Rhea M. Eckel.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Office for Local Government, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 387)
    Headed by Commissioner Sal J. Prezioso.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Office for Local Government, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 388)
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Office of Employee Relations, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 389)
    Headed by Director Melvin Osterman, Jr.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Office of General Services, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 390)
    Headed by Commissioner A. C. O'Hara.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Parks and Recreation, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 391)
    Headed by Commissioner Alexander Aldrich.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Public Service Commission, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 392)
    Headed by Joseph C. Swidler.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - State Consumer Protection Board, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 393)
    Headed by Chairman Peter M. Pryor.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - State University of New York, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 394)
    Headed by Chancellor Ernest L. Boyer.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Teller, Edward, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 395)
    Of Lawrencer Livermore Laboratory.
  - The Modern State in a Changing World - Welfare Inspector General, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 396)
    George F. Berlinger.
  - NAR Notes, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 397)
  - NAR Signed Stationery, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 398)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Agricultural Pollution Report, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 399)
    Program Staff report on the effects of Agricultural Pollution on Water Quality.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Agricultural Runoff Report, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 400)
    May 1974 report on the effects of Agricultural Runoff on Water Quality.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Budgets, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 401)
    1973 memo regarding the appropriation of funds for the NCWQ.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Conservation Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 402)
    Letter and report from the Foundation, offering their services to the Water Quality Commission.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Contract Materials - June 28, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 403)
    Materials issued to Commission members after the June 6, 1974 meeting.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 404)
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Cole, Kenneth R., 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 405)
    Special Assistant to President Ford.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Ehrlichman, John, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 406)
    Assistant to the President.
  - National Commission on Water Quality - Correspondence - Mitchell, Donna, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 407)
    Assistant to NAR on the NCWQ.